

Senior Systems Developer specializing in front end development. Experienced with all stages of the development cycle for dynamic web projects. Well-versed in numerous programming languages including HTML5, PHP OOP, JavaScript, CSS, MySQL. Strong background in project management and customer relations.

Part-Time Instructor – Senior Highs School specializing TVL-ICT and College of Computer Studies specializing programming languages, analytics, & Networking

BOI ARCHIEVALD A. RANAY

Phone:

+63 976 020 1190

E-Mail:

branay@uspf.edu.ph

Linkedin:

linkedin.com/boiarchievaldranay

Skill Highlights

- Project management
- Strong decision maker
- Complex problem solver
- Creative design
- Innovative
- Service-focused
- Programming
- Networking
- Data Analysis

Technology Prof.

Google Admin, Google Workspace, cPanel, FileZilla, Microsoft Applications, Canvas LMS, MySQL, R Programming, WordPress, Web Frameworks, Algorithms, Microsoft Server, Amazon Cloud.

Work Experience

01/2015 to 10/2022

Senior Systems Developer

University of Southern Philippines Foundation

- Responsible for managing and leading the system development unit and operation of the systems development group in an academic or administrative environment.
- Cooperate with designers to create clean interfaces and simple, intuitive interactions and experiences.
- Develop project concepts and maintain optimal workflow.
- Work with junior developers to manage large, complex design projects for the university.
- Complete detailed programming and development tasks for front end public and internal websites as well as challenging back-end server code.
- Carry out quality assurance tests to discover errors and optimize usability.

06/2016 to Present

Part-Time Instructor – SHS

University of Southern Philippines Foundation

 Specializing Technical Vocational Course – ICT focusing networking and computer hardware

06/2015 to Present

Part-Time Instructor – CCS University of Southern Philippines Foundation

• Specializing Programming languages, web systems and technologies, networking administration, and data structure

Educational Background

• 2021 – Present	Master of Science in Computer Science Cebu Institute of Technology - University Accumulated Units (15 units)
• 2018 – 2019	Master of Information Technology University of San Jose - Recoletos Accumulated Units (9 units)
• 2016 – 2018	Bachelor of Science in Computer Science University of Southern Philippines Foundation
• 2010 – 2014	Bachelor of Science in Information Technology Magna Cum Laude University of Southern Philippines Foundation
• 2006 – 2010	Basic Education University of Southern Philippines Foundation

Certificate and Awards

Microsoft Innovative Educator Expert

2020 – 2021, 2021 - 2022, 2022 - 2023

• Over-All Winner of 1st Lockton Legacy Awards for Innovation

(iBasuraIT) – Outstanding Adviser

• Certified Apple Teacher and Swift Teacher

August 2, 2019

• Certified Microsoft Innovative Educator

July 19, 2019

• 2nd Best Paper | College of Computer Studies

February 23, 2018

Research and Development

Lockton Philippines Legacy Awards Overall Grand Prize Winner

iBasuralT: Online Monitoring and Tracking Solution of Smart Solid Waste Containers

Philstar: https://www.philstar.com/opinion/2019/12/08/1975175/locktonlegacy-

awards

In-House Developed RFID System

Cebu Daily News: https://cebudailynews.inquirer.net/108811/uspfinaugurates-

university-developed-rfid-system

Certifications

November 8, 2022 Complete Ethical Hacking – Bug Bounty

Udemy | 17 Hours Total

Certificate: https://bit.ly/3gUCaY5

October 26, 2021 AWS Academy Graduate - AWS Academy Cloud

Foundations | Amazon Web Services and Certification

40 Hours

Certificate: https://bit.ly/3XUuKVu

September 27, 2021 Resource Speaker

UI & UX Design | Mobile Dev.

University of Southern Philippines Foundation

August 20, 2021 Resource Speaker

Designing Infographics

College of Computer Studies

University of Southern Philippines Foundation

• November 20, 2021 Data Visualization Fundamentals

Smarter Philippines through Data Analytics, R&D,

Training and Adoption

8 Hours

October 16, 2021 Data Management Fundamentals

Smarter Philippines through Data Analytics, R&D,

Training and Adoption

8 Hours

March 21, 2021 Essential Excel Skills for Data Preparation and Analysis

Smarter Philippines through Data Analytics, R&D,

Training and Adoption

8 Hours

References

• Lester B. Gastala – Former VP-ICT

University of Southern Philippines Foundation lgastala@uspf.edu.ph

• Armon Clark Tumanda – Former Asst. Manager

University of Southern Philippines Foundation ctumanda@uspf.edu.ph

Mrs. Vanessa Cheng

Head of Administration | Carmelab Diagnostic Center admin@carmelabdiagnostic-center.com